

Front End Web Developer

310 Abbotts Close Alpharetta, GA 30005

(678) 643.1596

thomasaheaton@gmail.com Portfolio | https://taheaton.github.io

https://github.com/taheaton

PROFILE

Having been in sales, consulting, banking and finance for the past 15 years, I am pursuing my latest passion ... web development and creation.

My work has been primarily in JavaScript, HTML, and CSS and in tandem with backend rails and mobile frameworks. Here is a complete list of the various tools I have used.

PROGRAMMING	STYLE	WORKFLOW	ADDITIONAL
HTML5 JavaScript Angularjs Reactjs	CSS3 SASS Foundation Bourbon/Neat	Gulp Bower Git/Github	Microsoft Office Google Docs Parse (for API data)
jQuery			

EXPERIENCE

Front End Engineer, The Iron Yard

Atlanta, Ga -2015

A 12 week course of intensive learning, in front end web development. The overall goal of this type of education is to place its graduates into real world scenarios within development teams, armed with the tools needed to complete design goals and deadlines.

- Completed over 20 projects designed to enhance web development knowledge
- Worked with Rails engineers to design and implement RESTful JSON APIs for web applications
- Worked intently with JavaScript frameworks and libraries including: Angularjs, Reactjs, and jQuery
- Designed multiple web apps following multiple Photoshop design files (PSD)

Vice President, Commercial Lending, The Piedmont Bank

Norcross, Ga -2014 - 2015

Privately-held banking and loan operations

COMPREHENSIVE ANALYSIS

Using Sageworks, tax records, company financials, and CPA documents to analyze global financials, decision loans and provide consultation

LENDING

"Full Stack" loan administration from underwriting to closing, funding approvals on credit and monitoring basis, and client retention.

CUSTOMER SERVICE AND SALES

New account acquisition, documentation, loan packaging, presenting loan requests to the officers and Board of Directors, and managing client accounts.

RESULTS

Fifteen new loan relationships acquired in less than 1 year.

Regional Finance Coordinator, North American Mission Board

Alpharetta, Ga -2011 - 2014, 2002 - 2006

Private equity fund coordination involving account management, analysis, lending, and acquisition

ACCOUNT MANAGEMENT

Strategic marketing designed to drive market awareness and increase key spheres of influence.

ANALYSIS

Loan portfolio analysis including comprehensive underwriting, renewing loan notes and developing workout strategies for non-performing assets

LENDING

Administer loans where appropriate as part of corporate investment strategy ACQUISITION

Select real estate for purchase involving a variety of due diligence applications to ensure sound investment

Business Development and Sales, Injoy Stewardship Services

Suwanee, GA - 2009 - 2011

Commercial Loan Officer, BB&T

Alpharetta, GA - 2006 - 2009

EDUCATION

Master of Business Administration, Georgia State University

Atlanta, GA - 2001

Bachelor of Arts, History, University of Georgia

Athens, GA - 1995

OTHER INTERESTS

Music (singing, choral directing) | Sports (tennis, golf) | Coaching (football, baseball) | Reading

			С	

The Iron Yard		The Piedmont Bank	North American Mission Board		
Jo Albright	Tim Whitacre	Bob Cash	Ty Salter	Jimmy Thompson	
404.434.5021	770.751.8046	678.644.6222	678.602.5346	678.232.9294	

OTHERS AVAILABLE UPON REQUEST